<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on zerθsrv</title>
    <link>https://0srv.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on zerθsrv</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 17:48:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://0srv.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Toolbox (WN31)</title>
      <link>https://0srv.com/posts/2021w31/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 17:48:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</author>
      <guid>https://0srv.com/posts/2021w31/</guid>
      <description>This is The Weekly Toolbox, week 31 of 2021. We have three Go programs and a security framework document.
Dasel A command line program written in GO for editing, transforming, and converting various data interchange formats. According to the feature set it can handle JSON, TOML, YAML, XML, and CSV. It&amp;rsquo;s an alternative to jq or yq. I think those are more popular in this category of tools. The project repository has a GIF loop to demo its functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iyclo</title>
      <link>https://0srv.com/posts/iyclo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 16:35:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</author>
      <guid>https://0srv.com/posts/iyclo/</guid>
      <description>In a past gig, I was tasked to evaluate container schedulers. The usual suspects Kubernetes and Nomad were the contenders. One huge caveat with the whole exercise is that containers are being scheduled within AWS. You have EKS and ECS but can&amp;rsquo;t move it to on-premises infrastructure in case an inexplicable reason comes up. Looking closely at these schedulers, they are designed for bare-metal fleets. If you have servers across multiple data centers, like a CDN, then Kubernetes is the best out there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weekly Toolbox (WN30)</title>
      <link>https://0srv.com/posts/2021w30/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 19:21:03 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</author>
      <guid>https://0srv.com/posts/2021w30/</guid>
      <description>A week wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go by without stumbling upon a new tool or service. Instead of committing to memory why not commit to Git and create a semipermanent record? Not limited to opensource, I will also feature commercial products occasionally found rummaging through product placements or news.
Occasionally posted these on Twitter but organization and recall are horrible. Would also like to write a few words about the tool and any experience with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CryptoHack</title>
      <link>https://0srv.com/posts/cryptohack/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 12:44:39 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</author>
      <guid>https://0srv.com/posts/cryptohack/</guid>
      <description>This week I have been solving the challenges at cryptohack.org. The past three days were a blast. Bit fiddling, hex buckling adventure. Did my last CTF more than a decade ago. There&amp;rsquo;s a mix of math, coding, and brain teasers.
The challenges are grouped in the following categories.
 General Mathematics Block Ciphers RSA Diffie-Hellman Elliptic Curves Miscellaneous Crypto on the Web  I&amp;rsquo;m bad at math so most of my points are from the problems that required coding and brain teasers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Kind Demo</title>
      <link>https://0srv.com/posts/a-kind-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 17:50:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</author>
      <guid>https://0srv.com/posts/a-kind-demo/</guid>
      <description>Most of the DevOps interview assignments involving Kubernetes suggest using minikube. I believe the intent is to gauge a basic understanding of containers and related DevOps tasks. I have skills far from a Kubernetes expert but I hope the interviewing team won&amp;rsquo;t mind if we do a bit of experimenting.
Looking around, I see there are more options for local Kubernetes clusters. I find the kind project a very promising contender.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Strategy</title>
      <link>https://0srv.com/posts/testing-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 17:50:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</author>
      <guid>https://0srv.com/posts/testing-strategy/</guid>
      <description>A testing strategy that applies to a wide range of software from ToDo to DeFi apps. What&amp;rsquo;s that like? Here&amp;rsquo;s my take on this turbulent topic.
In software, engineers are not engineers by trade. Definitions are mostly made up. Some are luckily agreed upon. A popular software engineer can redefine terms as they see fit and turn public perspective. What I call functional might be integration in someone’s vocabulary. Hopefully, the supporting text might clarify a particular perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File Sharing</title>
      <link>https://0srv.com/posts/file-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 17:50:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</author>
      <guid>https://0srv.com/posts/file-sharing/</guid>
      <description>So you want to send an email with a confidential attachment. Maybe you just want some privacy. It is reasonable and should be easy. Yes, modern messaging platforms exist but email is so sturdy because of its ubiquity and federated nature.
The Internet standards for email encryption are PGP and S/MIME but no one seems to use them. Properly using PGP or S/MIME requires senders and recipients to be configured to use either.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FortiGate x SonicWall</title>
      <link>https://0srv.com/posts/fortigate-x-sonicwall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 17:50:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <author>nopkart@gmail.com (Ed)</author>
      <guid>https://0srv.com/posts/fortigate-x-sonicwall/</guid>
      <description>This comparison of network equipment was commissioned by a client. I am evaluating Fortinet and SonicWall products. No practical testing was done. This will be a factual objective comparison using publicly available information. Hopefully, the reader will integrate my findings with their own evaluation criteria.
The first impression from my client’s demo experience is that Fortigate had the best coordination and quickest turnaround. SonicWall had some difficulty and delays but eventually delivered a working demo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
